bash a command language interpreter for interacting with a computer from the
bash 一种用于从命令行与计算机交互的命令语言解释器，
command line it's also called a shell because it surrounds the operating
它也被称为 shell，因为它围绕着
system kernel to hide its intricate details while allowing you the
操作系统内核以隐藏其复杂的细节，同时允许
programmer to do important stuff like access data and write files by typing
程序员通过输入简单的命令来执行重要的事情，例如访问数据和写入文件
simple commands this was a revolutionary concept when it was developed in the
这是一个革命性的概念，它是在 70 年代初开发的，
early 70s back when programmers were still using punch cards the shell
当时程序员仍在使用打孔卡。shell
concept evolved over the years with the bourne shell being the most popular
概念经过多年演变，bourne shell 是最受欢迎的
version that is until 1989 when the born-again shell or bash came about when
版本，直到 1989 年重生的 shell 或 bash 出现 关于当
you open up the terminal on a unix machine like mac os and most linux
你在像 mac os 和大多数 Linux
distros the default shell is usually bash it provides a prompt where you can
发行版这样的 unix 机器上打开终端时，默认的 shell 通常是bash 它提供了一个提示，你可以在其中
type a command which will then be interpreted by the shell and executed on
键入一个命令，然后由 shell 解释并在操作系统上执行
the operating system to find out if you're running bash type in which dollar
以查找 如果你在命令行中运行 bash 类型的美元
sign shell from the command line it's like any other application that lives in
符号 shell，它就像任何其他应用程序一样存在于
the binaries directory but bash is also a programming language that allows us to
t 他是二进制目录，但 bash 也是一种允许我们编写脚本的编程语言，
write scripts which means anything we type manually into the command line can
这意味着我们在命令行中手动键入的任何内容都
be automated with code when you first launch the shell it actually runs a
可以在您首次启动 shell 时使用代码自动化，它实际上运行
startup script that's defined in the bash profile or bashrc file on your
在bash 配置文件中定义的启动脚本或 bashrc 文件，
system this allows you to customize the behavior and appearance of the shell
这允许您在启动新会话时自定义shell 的行为和外观，
whenever you start a new session you can add your own custom bash scripts to any
您可以通过创建一个以点 sh 结尾的文件来将您自己的自定义 bash 脚本添加到任何
project by creating a file that ends in dot sh for no file extension at all the
项目中，完全没有文件扩展名
first line in that file should always be a shebang followed by the path to the
该文件中的第一行应该始终是 shebang，后跟
application that should run it below that we can start writing commands like
应该运行它的应用程序的路径，我们可以开始编写诸如
echo to print something and they'll be interpreted line by line to create a
echo 之类的命令来打印某些内容，它们将逐行解释以创建
variable type a name in all caps followed by the equal sign then
变量类型名称 所有大写字母后跟等号，然后
reference it later in the script using a dollar sign in front of the name now to
在脚本中稍后在名称前使用美元符号引用它现在
execute the script simply type the file name into the shell that was easy but
执行脚本只需将文件名输入到 shell 这很简单，
what if we want to pass in some arguments when we run the script
但是如果我们想在运行脚本时传递一些参数，
positional arguments will automatically be assigned variable names of 1 2 3 and
位置参数将自动分配变量名 1 2 3
so on now in other cases you may need additional user input in the middle of a
等等，现在在其他情况下，您可能需要在脚本中间进行额外的用户输入
script you can create loops in bash like a do while loop here that will prompt
您可以在 bash 中创建循环，如 do while 循环，这将
the user to continue the script on a yes answer or exit on a no answer from there
提示用户在是回答时继续脚本或在否回答时退出，
we can implement conditional logic with an if statement which will test if the
我们可以使用 if 语句实现条件逻辑，该语句将测试
value on the left side is less than the value on the right side if true then run
值是否在 左侧小于右侧的值，如果为 true，则运行
this command otherwise run the else command another cool feature is that if
此命令，否则运行 else命令另一个很酷的功能是，如果
you have multiple long running processes you can run them in parallel in the
您有多个长时间运行的进程，您可以
background by adding an ampersand after the command this has been bash the
通过在命令后添加 & 号在后台并行运行它们这已经
born-again shell in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like this
是 100 秒内重生的外壳，如果你想看更多这样的短视频，请
make sure to hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and i will
确保点击喜欢按钮并订阅感谢观看，我
see you in the next one
会在下一个 o 氖